Finding Aid for the Ralph Greenson Papers LSC.1497
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Published papers
  - The non-transference relationship in the psychoanalytic situation, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Intl. Journal of Psycho-analysis. Original and 2 copies.
  - Nontransference relationship in the psychosomatic situation [discussion of], 1970 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Intl. Journal of Psycho-analysis. 3 copies and 3 versions.
  - The exceptional position of the dream in psychoanalytic practice, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Psychoanalytic Quarterly. Original, 2 copies, edited copy and introduction.
  - A dream while drowning, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Reprint, "Separation - Individuation", essays in honor of M. Mahler. 3 copies and typescript.
  - The "real" relationship between the patient and the psychoanalyst, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Reprint, "The unconscious today", essays in honor of Max Schur. Typescript and 3 copies.
  - Beyond transference & interpretation, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - California earthquake 1971: Some psychoanalytic observations, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Greenson / T. Minthz. Int'l Journal of Psychoanalytic Psychotherapy. 3 copies.
  - The voice of the intellect is a soft one, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Review of Anna Freud. Int'l Journal of Psycho-analysis. 3 copies.
  - Talent & genius by K.R. Eissler [book review], 1973 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Israel Annals of Psychiatry. 4 copies.
  - The personal meaning of perfection, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Published in "Teilhard de Chardin: In quest of the perfection of man." Typescript and 2 copies.
  - In quest of the perfection of Man, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    2-day symposium held at San Francisco 1971 - registration material.
  - On transitional objects & transference, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Explorations. 2 typescripts and correspondence.
  - Loving, hating & indifference toward the patient, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Intl. Journal of Psycho-analysis.
  - The theory of psychoanalytic technique, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Chapter in American Handbook of Psychiatry.
  - Transference: Freud or Klein, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Intl. Journal of Psycho-analysis. Correspondence re Freud or Klein.
  - Transference: Freud or Klein - comments & correspondence, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Decline & fall of the 50-minute hour, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Journal of the American Psychoanalytic Association. 4 copies.
- Seminar
  - [Unidentified Notes], no date (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Short stories
  - The beloved whip - derived from a patient in Vienna, no date (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - My patient Harrison, no date (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - My father the doctor, no date (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Technique & Practice of Psychoanalysis, Vol. II
  - Introduction, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Chapter 5 contents, no date (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - 5.11 Introduction, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - 5.12 Initial phone call, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - 5.13 The analyst's office, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - 5.2 Selecting patients for psychoanalytic treatment: Analyzability, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    July. Selecting patients for psa treatment, 5.21 - 5.24.
  - 5.22 [not complete], no date (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - 5.23 Indications & contra-indications, no date (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - 5.23 Controversial issue of psych. testing, no date (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - 5.23 Psych. testing, no date (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - 5.24 Analyzability - an introduction, no date (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - 5.3: Criteria for analyzability, 5.31: Motivation & 5.311: The patient's motivation, no date (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - 5.312 The analyst's motivation, no date (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - References to Vol. II - end notes, no date (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Notes - handwritten as outline for Chapter 5, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    March.
  - Preliminary interviews, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    Lecture. June.
  - Leites on Vol. II, no date (Box 19, Folder 28)
    RRG & N. Leites taped.
  - Critique of psychological testing, no date (Box 19, Folder 30)
    Outline. RRG & Leites.
  - Problems in the interpretation of transference, no date (Box 19, Folder 31)
    Outline by RRG.
  - Analyzability, no date (Box 19, Folder 32)
    Lecture.
  - Importance of the initial interview, no date (Box 19, Folder 33)
    3 drafts.
  - Points to be added, no date (Box 19, Folder 34)
    Holograph notes.
  - Notes from literature, no date (Box 19, Folder 35)
    Holograph.
  - Memo to RRG on Technique, no date (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Technique - analysis regarding the overcoming of resistance, no date (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Memo, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    27 April.
- Technique [cassettes]
  - [1 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    28 September.
  - [2 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    28 September, 6 October.
  - [3 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    13 October.
  - [4 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    27 October.
  - [5 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - [6 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    3 November.
  - [7 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    10 November.
  - [8 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    24 November.
  - [9 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    1 December.
  - [10 of 10], 1971 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    8 December.
- Technique of Psychoanalysis, Vol. II
  - Outline of the chapters, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Notes, no date (Box 37, Folder 4)
- Unpublished papers
  - Food addiction, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Some remarks on countertransference, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - On negation and denial, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    2 versions, discussion by Milt Wexler.
  - Drugs in the psychotherapeutic situation, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    UCLA Center for Health Sciences: conference on drugs.
  - On resistance, defense and technique, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    APA meeting, Atlantic City.
  - Marriage: A psychoanalytic approach, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Los Angeles Institute for Psychoanalysis - Extension Division
  - Is there a sexual revolution?, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    For the Los Angeles Times. 2 copies.
  - The bold partnership in education, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Center for Early Education - Dedication Day
  - The unique patient-therapist relationship in borderline patients, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Joint meeting of American Psychoanalytic Association and American Psychiatric Association.
  - On kidney transplant patients, donors and doctors, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Abstract For International PSA meeting, Vienna.
  - The clinical use of the dream early in analysis, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Topeka Psychoanalytic Society.
  - Contribution to the panel on termination, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    APA meeting, Denver, Colorado.
  - Remarks on the changing use of dreams in psychoanalytic practice, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Psychoanalysis comes to the West Coast, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Los Angeles APA meeting.
  - The older analyst, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    The Los Angeles Psychoanalytic Society and Institute.
  - The transition to free association, no date (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - A contribution to the technique of dealing with our own errors in technique, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - The use of dream sequences for detecting and handling errors of technique, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Errors of authority, no date (Box 18, Folder 19)
    Comments by Dr. Jawetz.
  - Comments on errors in psychotherapy, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Management of errors in technique, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Errors in technique: detection, source and management, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Countertransference, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    Rough draft and handwritten version.
  - Special problems in psychotherapy with the rich and famous, 1978 (Box 39)
    Box 18, folder 24 is closed until January 1, 2039. Stored in Box 39.
- West Los Angeles Mental Health Center
  - Proposals, 1958 - 1959 (Box 32, Folder 4)
- Wilhelm Stekel
  - Case histories with Wilhelm Stekel in Vienna, 1935 - 1936 (Box 30, Folder 11)